Leo (Ilias) Giouldasis

Engineering Manager

Athens, Greece · leogiouldasis.com · linkedin.com/in/leo-giouldasis · leo.giouldasis@gmail.com

Engineering Manager with 4 years of experience leading and scaling engineering teams in fast-growing organizations. With over 10 years in the tech industry, I've honed my technical expertise, particularly in back-end development using nodeJS, Golang, and PHP. I have effectively initiated projects and guided them to completion, led distributed teams, and consistently achieved desired outcomes. Actively coached, mentored, and incentivized team members in their careers remotely, all while maintaining a team's positive spirit and motivation. My proactive and solution-oriented approach, combined with a foundation in technical knowledge, positions me to discuss and tackle complex challenges head-on.

Relevant WORK EXPERIENCE

eFood.gr

Engineering Manager

Jan. 2016 - Aug. 2023

- As an engineering manager I bootstrapped and led to completion more than 3 full stack projects, and numerous microservices or apis for the company.
- I've actively guided and mentored remote teams comprising up to 10 members, all reporting directly to me.
- Ensured deliverability of OKRs, strengthened best practices and engineering processes.

Spotawheel.gr (startup)

Software engineer (part time)

Apr. 2016 - Present

- One of the 2 main engineers to develop the mvp web application for this new service
- Responsible for maintaining their in house CRM panel and also developing api connections with big auto companies around europe.

Sevenplans Gmbh

Jan. 2015 - Jan. 2016

Software engineer

- I was responsible for designing, building and deploying a web application that showcased analytical graphs and reports. (Startup)
- Built custom apis for data accessing.

Thrives (startup)

Jan. 2013 - Jan. 2014

Backend engineer

 Responsible for building custom api endpoints to retrieve data from social media apis of the time like facebook, twitter and instagram.

EDUCATION

University Of Piraeus
Bachelor's Degree, Department of Informatics

SKILLS

- Technical Skills: Backend languages (GO, NodeJs, PHP), Frontend languages (html5, react), Git, SQL, mongo, redis, Solidity (web3),
- **Soft Skills :** Team management and Leadership, mentoring, communication, empathy, adaptability, Decision-making skills, willingness to learn

INTERESTS

Web3 and Defi, trading, tech-savvy, traveling, biking